Nishanth Thiyakarajan

+91 9976738856.

PROFILE OBJECTIVE

Looking for job in data science domain with 1.5+ years of IT experience where I can utilize my statistical and professional skills. As a passionate data analyst, I have completed some internships through some hands-on projects. Young and energetic individual with an agile learning mind who is keen to contribute to the cause.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai.

05/2021 - Present

• Assistant System Engineer

- Automation of manual BAU activities through the implementation of SQL methodologies and Unix shell scripting with improved reliability and accuracy.
- o Creating and maintaining data in Clarity PPM as an Application ASG(Admin).
- Raising, Maintaining and resolving the Change Requests(CR's), Service Requests(SR's), Incident Requests (IR's) for the applications in SNOW (Service NOW).

Data Analytics and Visualization Projects, GitHub.

06/2022 - Present

• **Details of Data Science Jobs** Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn)

• Superstore Income Source Excel (Pivot tables, VBA)

Top 200 YouTube Channels
Movies DB
Tableau
SQL(Basics)

• Website DB SQL(Intermediate) – used UTM's to get the Data.

Web Scrapping Using Python Python(Pandas, BeautifulSoup, Requests)

KEY SKILLS

Programming Languages
Python, C, Basics of Solidity, Linux.

Database Management System MySQL

Professional Applications Clarity PPM, ServiceNow.
Software Tools MS Excel, Tableau, Power Bl.

INTENSHIPS / CERTIFICATIONS / AWARDS

- Completed the Certification of, **Python E2**, **MySQL E2** from TCS.
- Completed the **Tableau Desktop Professional** Certificate.
- Completed the **Excel and SQL** Internship at Pantech Solutions LTD.

EDUCATION

B.E COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2017 - 2021

Kongu Engineering College, Perundurai, 75.30%

HSC 2016-2017

Rajalakshmi Gengusamy Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Pedappampatti, 80.08%

SSLC 2014-2015

Rajalakshmi Gengusamy Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Pedappampatti, 90.80%

PERSONAL DETAILS



D.O.B 29-05-1999

Languages Known

- English
- Tamil
- Telugu
- Malayalam

Personal Traits

- Resilient
- Leadership skills.
- Team Player.

Area of Interest

- Data Analytics and Visualization
- Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning.
- Web3